[
    {
        "question": "Abram cwæð to Lothe '(<em>ic</em>) #### sind gebroðru⁠ — Abraham said to Lot: 'We two are brothers'",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wit (<em>ic</em>) #### in ðære burnan baðodan⁠ — We two washed ourselves in that brook",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Crist þonne wat (<em>ic</em>) #### clænnyss⁠ — Christ is the water of our purity",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nu ic eom orwena ðæt (<em>ic</em>) #### seo eðylstæf afre weorþe gifede ætgædere⁠ — Now I am hopeless that the staff of our family will ever be given to us two together",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif (<em>þu</em>) #### ðæt fæsten fyre willaþ forstandan⁠ — If you two will protect that fastness from fire",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Swa (<em>þu</em>) #### se balewa het⁠ — So the baleful one commanded you two ",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic nu ðis þing write to ðe gemanelice and to minre meder and minum geswustrum forðon (<em>þu</em>) #### lufu sceal beon somod gemane⁠ — I now write this thing to you together, to my mother and my sister, because the love of you both shall be mutual ",
        "correctAnswer": "incer",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'incer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt wylle git ðæt ic (<em>þu</em>) #### do?⁠ — What do you two wish I do for you two?",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða wæron (<em>ic</em>) #### twegen on anum olfende þurh þæt rume westen⁠ — Then we two were on a camel travelling through that enormous desert",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### he bitere forgeald⁠ — He bitterly repaid us",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðanne gæornlicæ of þam god geþæncæ and for (<em>ic</em>) #### sawle geornlicæ beo⁠ — Remember God diligently from the property and be diligent for our two souls",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### is his hyldo þearf⁠ — for us two his favour is a necessity ",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>þu</em>) #### sindon bigswicon⁠ — You two are deceivers",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>þu</em>) #### forgeaf balewe geþohtas⁠ — He inspired you with wicked thoughts",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ac git waron æt þisse wydewan hame and þær þus (<em>þu</em>) #### lif leofodon⁠ — But you were at the home of a widow, and there passed your time in wisdom",
        "correctAnswer": "incer",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'incer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>ic</em>) #### her baru standaþ unwered wædo⁠ — we two stand here naked, unprotected by garments",
        "correctAnswer": "wit",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'wit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wit (<em>ic</em>) #### gefyldan niowes ceses⁠ — We filled ourselves with new cheese",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual accusative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wit geseagon (<em>ic</em>) #### feond forwordene⁠ — We two saw our enemy perish",
        "correctAnswer": "uncer",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual genitive so it becomes 'uncer'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "God mæg foreaðe (<em>ic</em>) #### æt foresceawian⁠ — God can very easily provide food for us two",
        "correctAnswer": "unc",
        "explanation":"Here 'ic' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'unc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": " Gangaþ ut (<em>þu</em>) #### godwrecan⁠ — Come out ye two wretches",
        "correctAnswer": "git",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual nominative so it becomes 'git'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>þu</em>) #### sceal worn fela maðma gemænra⁠ — To you two shall be a great many common treasures",
        "correctAnswer": "inc",
        "explanation":"Here 'þu' is used in the first person dual dative so it becomes 'inc'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]